Caleb Rowlands

£ +447803295194

: https://calartrow.github.io/

thin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/calrow

About Me

As a career changer transitioning from over four years in ground engineering to the tech industry, I offer a wealth of transferable skills and experience in project delivery. I have recently completed an MSc in Computing, where I gained proficiency in a range of programming languages, culminating in a dissertation utilising the MERN tech stack. I've honed my professional skills on large-scale infrastructure projects in the UK, strengthening my communication, professionalism, and collaboration abilities. I am keen to apply my diverse skill set within the tech sector. I am committed to continue learning and developing as an individual and prepared to learn any new programming languages and technologies.

Skills

HTML, CSS, Python, Javascript, React, SQL, Git, Visual Studio Code, Agile Methodologies

Education

MSc Computing, Cardiff University

(2022–2023) TBC - (Distinction taught element) Related modules: Fundamentals of Programming, Software engineering, Algorithms, Data Structures and Programming, Databases and Modelling

BSc (Hons) Geology, University of Plymouth (2014–2017) 1st Class

Employment History

Ground Investigation Reporting Engineer, Structural Soils Ltd. (RSK) (2019–2022)

- Conducted data quality reviews and interpretation, showcasing strong attention to detail
- o Communicated technical findings to project clients, demonstrating client-facing skills.
- Worked closely with cross-functional teams, highlighting abilities in team collaboration and project management.
- Managed document control for two major contracts, demonstrating aptitude in version control.
- o Took charge of project data management, showing expertise in handling large data sets.

o Exhibited problem-solving abilities by resolving client data queries.

Data Processor, Structural Soils Ltd. (RSK) (2017–2019)

- Conducted quality assurance checks on data records.
- Liaised with senior engineers and clients, evidencing strong communication skills.
- o Maintained project monitoring tools.
- Facilitated timely data delivery to clients and senior staff, demonstrating efficiency and time management.
- o Transcribed field data into a database, showing proficiency in data handling and conversion.
- Conducted meticulous additional checks on records, illustrating a commitment to quality and accuracy.

Geochemistry Intern, Instituto Volcanológico de Canarias (INVOLCAN) (Sep 2017 - Oct 2017)

- Collaborated on scientific research project in geothermal exploration, focusing on soil degassing surveys
- o Collected and analysed soil gas samples using chemical and isotopic analysis techniques

Publications & Awards

- Soil gas He and H2 for surface geothermal exploration in Gran Canaria, Canary Islands -Geophysical Research Abstracts, EGU General Assembly 2018 https://meetingorganizer.copernicus.org/EGU2018/ EGU2018-10366-2.pdf
- Palaeontological Association Prize for Best Performance in Palaeontology 2015

Additional Information

- o **Elected Men's 1st team captain** University of Plymouth Tennis Club 2015 2016
- o **Elected Treasurer** University of Plymouth Tennis Club 2016-2017
- o Inclusion on the **Dean's list for exceptional** academic achievement BSc (hons) Geology; (2015), (2016), and Civil Engineering Stage 0 (2014)
- o Bilingual: English/Welsh

^{*} References available on request